sktthemes.net 2018-09-03

# Privacy Policy and GDPR - SKT Themes

**Our site SKT Themes plans to be fully compliant with GDPR starting 25th May 2018.**

**What is GDPR?**

GDPR stands for [General Data Protection Regulation](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/General_Data_Protection_Regulation) and is intended to strengthen and unify data protection for all individuals within the European Union. Its primary aim is to give control back to the EU residents over their personal data.

Why the urgency? Although the GDPR was introduced two years ago, it becomes  enforceable starting May 25, 2018.

As a customer of SKT Themes GDPR gives you new protection rights and assures better access to your personal data.

  1. **Right to rectification:** Rectify your personal information at any time from your account settings. You can also contact us directly to edit or rectify your information.
  2. **Right to be forgotten:** You can ask us to cancel your SKT Themes Account at any point of time or close your account. You can also send us request to erase all your data which will be completed within 30 days period.
  3. **Right to portability:** Upon request we will export all your data and give it to you for transfer to any third party or competitor.
  4. **Right to object:** We send monthly newsletters and you can unsubscribe at any point of time from them and also unsubscribe from any of our forum topics or ask us for the same.
  5. **Right to access:** We are transparent about the data we collect and what we do with it.

As part of the business activity of digital products and services SKT Themes is required to process personal data belonging to its customers/user/prospects.

Here is what we store into our database and here is what we never store as well:

**Personal Data:** We store personal data which is first name, last name, email address and phone number of user trying to purchase any theme or all themes package from our store.

**Processing of personal data:** We only send bi-monthly newsletters to your email address. We do not sell any of your data to any third party vendors. With GDPR compliance you can also ask us to remove your data.

**Card Details:** Credit card or other sensitive information is not at all stored with us and is handled directly with FastSpring Payment gateway ([Fastspring.com](http://fastspring.com/)) and PayPal payment gateway ([PayPal.com](http://paypal.com/)) which are used worldwide by prominent merchants across the globe.

**Cookie:** a cookie is information placed on an internet user’s hard disk by the server of a website he/she has visited. It contains several pieces of data: the name of the server that placed it there, an identifier with a unique number and possibly an expiry date. This information is sometimes stored on the computer as a simple text file which a server can access to read and save information.

Personal data provided by the user may only be disclosed to a third party in the following instances:

  * with the user’s authorization and confirmation that the owner of this personal data has personally authorized its disclosure;
  * at the request of legally competent authorities, upon presentation of a court order or within the context of a legal dispute.

Types of cookies used

**Cookies needed to navigate the website**

These cookies are needed for the skt themes website to operate properly. They allow the website’s main features to be used.

Without these cookies, users would not be able to use the website normally.

**Functional cookies**

These cookies allow a customized user experience to be provided.

**Analytical cookies**

These cookies allow website use and performance to be monitored and its operation to be improved by analyzing the traffic to information pages through the tracking of an individual’s open, click and bounce rates.

**Share button cookies**

Social media cookies allow users to share pages and content on third-party social networks via social media sharing buttons.

**Cookie management**

Users can accept or refuse cookies on a case by case basis, or refuse all cookies by adjusting their browser settings.

If the user chooses to refuse all cookies, access to some of the website’s pages will be limited.

Depending on which navigator the user has, cookies can be blocked as follows:

**Internet Explorer**

  * Click on the Tools button, then on Internet Options.
  * On the General tab, under Navigation History, click on Settings.
  * Click on the Display Files button.
  * Select the cookies you would like to block and click on Remove.

**Firefox**

  * Click on the Navigation Tools icon and select the Options menu.
  * In the window that opens, select Private Life and click on Display Cookies.
  * Select the cookies you would like to block and click on Remove.

**Safari**

  * Click on the Edit icon and select the Preferences menu.
  * Click on Security and then Display Cookies.
  * Select the cookies you would like to block and click on Remove.

**Google Chrome**

  * Click on the Tools icon, select the Options menu and then click on the Advanced
  * Options tab to access the Privacy section.
  * Click on the Display Cookies button.
  * Select the cookies you would like to block and click on Remove.

**Cookie retention period**

Cookies will be held on the user’s device for a maximum period of 13 months from the date the user gives consent.

Once this period has expired, consent will need to be given again.

**Security**

SendinBlue has taken all necessary precautions to safeguard personal data and, in particular, to prevent it from being misrepresented, damaged or accessed by an unauthorized third party.

These measures include the following:

  * Multi-level firewall,
  * Anti-virus with a proven reputation for detecting attempted intrusions,
  * Encrypted data transmission using SSL/HTTPS/VPN technology.

Moreover, persons from SendinBlue’s recipient departments wishing to access the data must be authenticated using an individual access code and password that are sufficiently robust and changed regularly.

Data processed via non-secure communication channels is subject to technical measures rendering it incomprehensible to any unauthorized person.

Any questions about the security of our website can be addressed to support@sktthemes.com.

Amendments to the Confidentiality Policy

SKT Themes reserves the right to amend this Confidentiality Policy to comply with any changes to the laws and regulations in force.

Any amendments will be communicated via our website or by email, as far as possible, at least thirty days before they come into force.
